hey everybody welcome to this a1
english listening practice video you can
use this video
to practice your listening and
comprehension
as i speak before we start remember to
subscribe to the channel
click on the bell and follow us on
instagram
you ready so today i'm gonna talk about
technology this is a great topic
because we all use technology every day
you're using technology to watch this
video
right now so let's talk about some
different kinds of technology today
one really important type of technology
is computer technology
computers today are much different than
computers from the past
20 or 30 years ago computers were really
limited
they couldn't do the things that
computers do today
in the past they were also really big
but today computers come in many
different sizes
computers today are fast powerful
and easy to use i remember when i
first started using the computer i was
six years old i liked playing computer
games
but all the games were very basic at
that time
i still thought they were really fun
today
computer games are very complex alright
now let's talk about cell phones when i
was a kid
not many people had cell phones most
people used
landlines which are phones inside your
house
nowadays not many people have landlines
everyone has cell phones now i remember
getting my first
cell phone when i was 12 years old
i thought it was so cool these days
phones are extremely important because
you can do
almost anything on your phone but i
think the most
important technology today is the
internet
most people use the internet every day
to do
many things people like me need the
internet
in order to work if i don't have
i can't work we also use the internet to
study
to shop and to entertain ourselves
i can't imagine not having the internet
i use it for many hours every day
how about you how many hours a day
do you use the internet okay now let's
talk about
technology of the past for example
one really important invention was the
motorized vehicle
or the car before cars people traveled
by
horse by foot or in other ways
when the car was invented people were
able to travel
more easily cars from the past looked
very different from today's cars i think
old cars looked pretty cool another
really
important invention was electricity
before electricity people had to use
candles and fire for light at night
the cities were much darker than today
nowadays our cities have so much light
at night
and of course we use electricity for so
many different things today
sometimes the electricity goes out and
everything stops working i hate when the
electricity goes out
one more important invention was the
television
in the past television was the greatest
form of entertainment everyone sat down
in the evenings
and watched tv nowadays more people
watch tv shows on their computers
like on netflix many young people
prefer doing everything on their
computer or cell phone
alright that's all for today leave a
comment and tell me what your favorite
technology is
and remember to subscribe to the channel
click on the bell
and follow us on instagram for more
english tips and lessons
i'll see you next time
[Music]
[Applause]
you